Alex Millar

UI/UX Designer

UI/UX Designer with a background in hospitality, teaching and Geology.

Skilled in solving problems with an empathetic mindset and bringing projects

<u>alexmillar@outlook.com</u>

+44 7776 673632



Bristol, UK LinkedIn



<u>Website</u>



UI/UX Projects

Portfolio Website May 2024

 Built a responsive portfolio website from scratch, writing clean and well-organised code in HTML, CSS & Java.

from concept to final product independently and with attention to detail.

 Used problem-solving skills to identify and fix bugs in the website, enhancing user-experience and functionality.

Thrive | Budgeting App | April 2024

- Conceptualised and built a prototype budgeting app that incentivises users who don't like working with finances.
- Created a responsive design for mobile & desktop breakpoints.
- Users are rewarded in the app by growing their own 'Money Trees'.

ShuttleShare | Badminton App | Jan - Feb 2024

- Created a social badminton app, designed to meet both iOS and Android mobile guidelines.
- Produced two prototypes with complex animations.
- Users are able to record matches they have played so they can track and compare stats with other users.

Professional Experience

Small Goods | Supervisor | Sep 2022 - Sep 2024

- Managed a team of 4, utilising communication skills and teamwork.
- Ensured sustained client satisfaction through organisation, time management and empathy.

200 Degrees | Head Barista | Apr 2021 - Aug 2022

• Trained team-members with zero experience, supporting them to achieve consistently high standards with attention to detail.

Apax English | ESL Teacher | Nov 2019 - Apr 2021

- Taught English in Vietnam to students in-person & online, adapting lessons based on their individual requirements.
- Managed 10 different classes independently, employing excellent listening skills, multitasking and creativity.
- Used problem solving and adaptability skills to meet students needs in a challenging environment during the COVID pandemic.

Skills

- UI & Graphic Design
- Basic HTML, CSS & Java
- · Competitive Analysis
- User Interviews
- User Personas
- User Flows
- Wireframing
- Logo Design
- Iconography
- Prototyping
- User Testing
- A/B Preference Testing

Tools

- Figma
- · Visual Studio Code
- · MS Office Suite
- InkScape
- Github

Education

CareerFoundry

Jun 2023 - May 2024

Certificate in UI Design with specialisation in Frontend Development.

Plymouth University

Sep 2013 - Jul 2016

BSc (Hons) in Geology, receiving a 2:1.